Hello everyone, and welcome to Introduction to Calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好，欢迎与Wolfram U一起学习微积分入门。
My name is Devendra Kapadia, and I work here at Wolfram Research
我叫Devendra Kapadia，我在Wolfram Research工作
as a kernel developer for calculus functions. But I also enjoy teaching mathematics,
作为微积分功能的内核开发人员。但我也喜欢教数学
and it’s a great pleasure to have this opportunity to talk about calculus with you.
很高兴有机会与您讨论微积分。
Now today is the first lesson, so I thought we would spend some time talking about what is calculus
今天是第一课，所以我想我们会花一些时间来讨论什么是微积分
and trying to understand what this beautiful subject is all about. I’ll begin by defining calculus,
并试图了解这个美丽的主题到底是什么。我将从定义微积分开始，
and then we’ll talk a little bit about the main problems of calculus, some history,
然后我们将讨论微积分的主要问题，一些历史，
and then I’ll tell you why you might want to study the course, and what the course is all about.
然后我会告诉你为什么要学习本课程，以及本课程的全部内容。
Let’s begin by answering the question what is calculus?
让我们首先回答以下问题：什么是微积分？
Well, very simply, calculus is the science of change. Now, change is all around us.
好吧，很简单，微积分是研究变化的科学。现在，变化无处不在。
For instance, the second hand on this clock changes its position every second, but you could have
例如，该时钟的秒针每秒都在更改其位置，但是您可以看到自然界中存在着
more complicated motion. For example, the planets in the solar system change their position
更复杂的运动。例如，太阳系中的行星在绕着太阳旋转的每个时刻
at every instant as they revolve around the sun. Now in the first case,
都在改变它的位置。现在在第一种情况下
for the motion of the second hand around a clock, you could use simple arithmetic algebra
对于秒针围绕时钟的运动，您可以使用简单的算术代数来分析问题，
to analyze a problem, but in more difficult cases like the solar system motion,
但是在更困难的情况下，例如研究太阳系运动，
you would need better tools to analyze the motion, and one such tool is calculus.
您将需要更好的工具来分析运动，而这样的工具之一就是微积分。
Calculus is an essential tool for deeply understanding change in a mathematical way, and hence,
微积分是一种以数学方式深刻理解变化的重要工具，因此，
it is a tool of choice for many scientific problems. The next question is
它是许多科学问题的首选工具。接下来我将阐述，
what are the main problems that drove the development of calculus?
导致微积分发展的主要问题是什么？
Well, the four main problems of calculus are first, the problem of finding the tangent line
微积分的四个主要问题如下：首先是寻找曲线上某一点处的切线的问题。
to a curve at a point. Now if the curve is sufficiently simple like a circle,
现在，如果曲线足够简单，如圆形，
you can of course draw the tangent line to the curve at that point, but in more complicated cases,
您当然可以在该点绘制曲线的切线，但是在更复杂的情况下，
you would need something like calculus to solve the problem.
您将需要微积分来解决问题。
Number two is the problem of finding the area under a curve.
第二个问题是找到曲线下的面积。
Now once again, if, let’s say, you have a circle, then finding the area is not very difficult.
现在再说一次，如果您有一个圆圈，那么求出该面积并不是很困难。
But for more complicated curves, you would need better tools. Now from the point of view
但是对于更复杂的曲线，您将需要更好的工具。现在来考虑物理问题
of physics, you might sometimes need to find, let’s say, the velocity the a particle
您有时可能需要找到一个给定位置和加速度的粒子的速度
given either its position or acceleration, and once again,
同样地，
you can use calculus to solve this problem.
您可以使用微积分解决此问题。
And finally, from time to time, you are going to want to either maximize or minimize some quantity,
最后，又是如果您想要最大化或最小化某些量，
and the common word for that is optimizing. For example, a businessman might want
（最常用的词就是优化）。例如，一个商人可能想要
to maximize his profits or minimize his loss, and once again, calculus is the tool
最大化他的利润或最小化他的损失，同样地，
which helps us to study the process of optimization.
微积分是我们研究优化过程的重要工具。
Okay. Let’s look at each of these in a bit more detail. Let’s start with tangent to a curve.
好了。我们现在来看一些更细节的东西。让我们从曲线的切线开始。
Let’s begin with the tangent to a curve. Now to find a tangent line at a point, what we do is
我们从曲线的切线开始。现在要找到一点的切线，我们要做的是
we draw the secant lines from nearby points. Let’s say we want to find a tangent at this point over here.
我们从附近的点画出割线。假设我们要在此处找到切线。
We start with a point, in this case far away, and let the secant line change
我们从一个点开始，在这种情况下，它很远，然后让割线改变
by moving the point along the curve. Let’s run this animation over here.
通过沿曲线移动点。让我们在这里运行该动画。
What you’ll see is that as the point moves to the required point,
您会看到，随着点移动到所需点，
the secant becomes closer and closer to the tangent. Okay. To summarize,
割线越来越接近切线。好的。总而言之，
as a secant gets closer to the desired point, you’re going to get the tangent line.
当割线接近所需的点时，您将得到切线。
Now onto the second problem for calculus, and that’s the problem of finding the area
现在到微积分的第二个问题，那就是求出区域面积
or length of a curve. Here is an animation in which we can talk about the area
或曲线的长度的问题。这是一个动画，我们可以在其中探究这个区域
of a regular polygon when the number of sides goes from 3 to 50. Let’s begin with the case of n = 3,
当边数从3变到50时，它变为正多边形。让我们从n = 3 的情况开始，
where you have a triangle, and then as you increase the number of sides, you see what happens
那里有一个三角形，然后随着边数的增加，您会看到发生了什么
the perimeter and the area. Let’s run animation. You see that as the number of sides increases,
周边和区域。让我们运行动画。您会看到随着边数的增加，
the polygon approaches the circumscribed circle. Of course in this case, you know that when you have
多边形接近外接圆。当然，在这种情况下，您知道
an infinite number of sides, then you get the area of the full circle, which is just π if the radius is 1.
如果你有无限多个边，则可以得到整个圆的面积，如果半径为1，那么面积就是π。
Okay. On to the third problem for calculus, and that is what is called the velocity problem.
好的。关于微积分的第三个问题，那就是速度问题。
Here we have a particle that is moving along around a knotted curve. At each stage, you have the velocity
在这里，我们有一个沿着打结曲线移动的粒子。在每个阶段，您都知道粒子
的速度
and the acceleration, so you have the tangent and the normal, as we call it,
和加速度，所以我们有切线和法线，如我们所说，
and the problem might be to compute the velocity and acceleration at any time in a very accurate way.
问题是如何精确计算任意时刻粒子的速度和加速度
Once again, you can use calculus for this.
再一次地，您可以为此使用微积分。
Finally, on to the problem of optimization. Let’s say a farmer has 500 feet of fencing available,
最后，讨论优化问题。假设一个农夫有500英尺的栅栏，
and the farmer wants to fence off a rectangle with the maximum area. The question is
农民想用最大面积的矩形围起来。问题是
what should the dimensions of the rectangle be? Let’s look at this interactive model over here.
矩形的尺寸应该是多少？让我们在这里看看这个交互式模型。
You see that as you change the dimensions, you get more and more area. It increases up to certain point,
您会看到，随着更改尺寸，您将获得越来越大的面积。它增加到一定程度，
and then it starts to shrink again. It would look like the best way to optimize over here would be
然后又开始收缩。看起来在这里进行优化的最佳方法是
to choose a rectangle which is, in fact, a square of 125 feet by 125 feet, but the question is
选择一个实际上是125英尺乘125英尺的正方形的矩形，但是问题是
how would you have arrived at the solution without trial and error?
您将如何在没有反复试验的情况下得出解决方案？
Calculus gives you a systematic way of solving such problems.
微积分为您提供了解决此类问题的系统方法。
Now of course the ancient Greeks knew quite a lot about solving such problems,
当然，古希腊人对此类问题已经有很多的认识，
but it was only in the 17th century that mathematicians started to look a little deeper into
但是直到17世纪，数学家才开始更深入地研究
how one could solve each of these four problems. The French lawyer and mathematician Pierre de Fermat
如何解决这四个问题。法国律师兼数学家Pierre de Fermat
developed a method for drawing tangents and finding maxima and minima.
发明了一种绘制切线并找到最大值和最小值的方法。
The clergymen John Wallis found ways, for example, to find the value of π/2 and do it quite accurately.
神职人员约翰·沃利斯（John Wallis）找到了一些方法来求出π/ 2的值并相当准确地做到这一点。
Johannes Kepler, the great astronomer, used the method of the Greeks to find
伟大的天文学家约翰尼斯·开普勒（Johannes Kepler）用希腊人的方法求出了
to find the volume of wine barrels, and in fact in doing so, he touched upon the questions of
酒桶的体积，实际上，他谈到了以下问题：
finding volumes and finding maxima and minima, so he really is one of the pioneers of calculus.
求出体积并找到其最大值和最小值，所以他确实是微积分的先驱之一。
Of course at that point, geometry was still the method of choice for many problems,
当然，在那时，几何仍然是许多问题的选择方法，
so Isaac Barrow in England showed how to calculate the tangent to a curve
所以英国的Isaac Barrow展示了如何使用纯粹的几何方法
using purely geometrical means. So Fermat, Wallis, Kepler and Barrow were the early pioneers
来计算曲线的切线。因此，费马，沃利斯，开普勒和巴罗是微积分以及许多其他方法的先驱。
of calculus, along with many others. Now you might read in books or elsewhere that
现在您可能会在书本或其他地方阅读到，
Newton and Leibniz discovered calculus. The question is
牛顿和莱布尼兹发现了微积分。问题是
in what sense are they regarded as pioneers and discovers of calculus in the true sense?
在什么意义上，他们被视为真正意义上的微积分的先驱和发现？
The point is that although the early mathematicians knew about calculus one way or the other,
关键是，尽管早期的数学家以某种方式发展了微积分，
it was only Newton and Leibniz who gave general methods for doing calculus.
只有牛顿和莱布尼兹给出了进行微积分的通用方法。
In fact, they put together all the earlier knowledge and found relations between
实际上，他们将所有前人的知识放在一起，并发明了
the various concepts of calculus. One question was who discovered calculus first?
微积分的各种概念。一个争论是谁首先发现了微积分？
Was it Newton or Leibniz? Well, Leibniz published his paper first,
是牛顿还是莱布尼兹？莱布尼兹首先发表了他的论文，
but then Newton had already shared his ideas on calculus with others. In England people said
但是后来牛顿已经与其他人分享了他关于微积分的想法。在英格兰，人们说
oh, Newton discovered calculus, while elsewhere in Europe, the support was all for Leibniz.
哦，牛顿发现了微积分，而在欧洲其他地方，人们都说莱布尼茨是微积分之父。
Well, today it doesn’t matter a lot, and we regard Newton and Leibniz as the joint creators of calculus,
今时今日，这些争论已经无关紧要了，我们认为牛顿和莱布尼兹是微积分的共同创造者，
for it was they who gave a unified way of looking at concepts in this subject to us,
因为正是他们为我们提供了一种统一的方式来研究这一主题的概念，
and today we talk of the Newton and Leibniz approach to calculus. Now beyond Newton–Leibniz,
今天我们讨论牛顿和莱布尼兹的微积分方法。现在超越牛顿-莱布尼兹，
people went on making improvements to calculus.
人们继续改进微积分。
The Bernoulli brothers were very active in this area. In fact, Johann Bernoulli wrote the first
伯努利兄弟在这一领域非常活跃。实际上，约翰·伯努利（Johann Bernoulli）写了第一本
the first differential calculus textbook informally; it was L’Hospital who actually published it.
第一本微积分学非正式的教科书；实际上它是医院出版的。
Maria Agnesi—lady mathematician—she was the eldest of 21 children, and still found time
玛丽亚·阿格尼丝（Maria Agnesi）-一位女数学家-她是21个孩子中的老大，寻找时间
to do calculus and write a book that covered both differential and integral calculus.
研究微积分并写一本涵盖微积分和积分的书。
But the modern foundations of calculus, what made it really nice and precise,
但是是微积分的现代基础使它变得非常精确，
were given by Cauchy and Weierstrass, and it was they who finally told us
这是柯西和维尔斯特拉斯给出的，是他们最终
how to approach calculus in a very rigorous and complete manner.
得出了处理微积分的非常严格和完整的方式。
Now although all these pioneers did a lot of work, things did not stop over there.
现在，尽管所有这些先驱者都做了很多工作，但事情并没有就此止步。
Even today, we have calculus being used in many, many areas. For example, quantum mechanics,
直到今天，微积分仍在许多领域中使用。例如量子力学
which is the study of matter at the atomic level, uses the Schrӧdinger equation,
这是在原子水平上对物质的研究，使用Schrӧdinger方程，
which is a product of calculus. If you go to financial markets, then the Black–Scholes equation is used
这是微积分的产物。在金融领域，则会使用Black–Scholes方程
to find the prices of options. The Black–Scholes equation, in fact, uses what are called
来计算期权的价格。实际上，Black-Scholes方程使用的是所谓的
partial differential equations. When Albert Einstein wanted to discover the laws of gravitation,
偏微分方程。当爱因斯坦想发现万有引力定律时，
he had to turn to calculus, something called Ricci calculus, and his friend Marcel Grossmann
他不得不求助于微积分学，即所谓的Ricci微积分学，他的朋友Marcel Grossmann
taught him the details, but Albert Einstein developed the so-called general theory of relativity
教会了他细节，但爱因斯坦根据微积分发展了
based on calculus. If you study economics and you want to study markets, you need calculus.
相对论。如果您学习经济学并且想学习市场运转规律，也需要微积分。
If you want to study medicine, you need calculus to figure out dosing strategies.
如果您想学习医学，则需要进行微积分计算剂量策略。
Of course even if you go to NASA, you would find that they use calculus all the time
当然，即使您去NASA，也会发现他们一直在使用微积分
to figure out how to design and how to propel their rockets. The point is calculus continues to be
去研究如何设计和推进火箭。微积分是许多不同领域的关键工具。
a key tool in many different areas. But you might ask okay, that’s fine;
但是你可能会问“OK，
it’s really useful to some people, but why is it useful to me?
它对某些人确实有用，但是为什么对我有用？”
Why should I study calculus? Well, I already gave the first reason. The first reason is that
我为什么要学习微积分？我已经给出了第一个理由。第一个原因是
it has very broad applications in the real world. The other point is a more practical one—
它在现实世界中具有非常广泛的应用。另一点是更实际的一点-
that if you are studying any kind of STEM degree in science or technology, then they would ask you
如果您正在攻读任何类型的科学或技术的STEM学位，那么他们会要求您
to first master calculus before doing anything else. It’s a prerequisite which you must go through
在做其他事情之前先掌握微积分。如果您想成为技术专家，
if you want to become a technical kind of person. Now on the other hand, you can say that
这是您必须经过的前提条件。另一方面，您可以说
I’m not going to go into any of these STEM fields; I just am going to pursue my own interests.
我将不打算涉及任何这些STEM领域。我只是为了追求自己的利益。
Well, that’s fine, but for anyone to master calculus represents a major academic milestone
这很好，但是对任何人而言，掌握微积分都是一个学术里程碑。
for that person, and to me, that is the main reason for studying calculus.
对我来说，这就是研究微积分的主要原因。
It is a major academic milestone. If at any point in your career you can say I know calculus,
这是一个重要的学术里程碑。如果您在职业生涯的任何时候都可以说我了解微积分，
that is a great feeling, and I hope you get it after going through this course.
这将会是一种很棒的感觉，我希望您在完成本课程后能得到它。
Okay. A little bit about the course itself. This course will have 40 lessons—it’s a 40-part course,
好的。有关课程本身的一些知识。本课程将有40节课，这是一个40部分的课程，
and roughly speaking, the course is based on the AP Calculus AB in this country, the US.
大致而言，该课程基于美国这个国家的AP Calculus AB。
The AP Calculus course is a pretty challenging high-school level course, and I thought that
AP微积分课程是一门颇具挑战性的高中课程，我
it would be good to get more people into studying calculus early and preparing themselves
希望有更多的人尽早学习微积分并做好
for applying it in their own careers. Now we’ll begin with standard topics like functions and limits,
将其应用于自己的职业的准备。现在，我们将从函数和极限之类的标准主题开始，
and having done that, we will move onto differential calculus and finally we will move on to integral calculus.
然后，我们将探讨微分，最后将探讨积分。
Don’t worry if you don't follow these terms; they’ll get familiar to you a little later on.
如果您还不了解这些主题的话，没关系，之后你将会熟悉它们
Of course the only way to learn calculus and mathematics is by doing, so there will be lots of
当然，学习微积分和数学的唯一方法是边做边学，因此会有很多
problem sessions and quizzes to help you understand calculus in a deeper and practical way.
问题会议和测验可帮助您以更深入和实用的方式理解微积分。
But the main point is that we will focus on understanding, and there will be almost no
但主要的一点是，我们将专注于理解，并且几乎没有
formal proofs for any theorems, so the advantage of that is that we can focus on visualization,
任何定理的形式证明，所以它的优点是我们可以专注于微积分的可视化，
on calculations, and really get familiar with all the things which are possible
并真正熟悉所有使用Mathematica和Wolfram语言
possible with Mathematica and the Wolfram Language. I do hope you’ll take advantage of this course
可以做到的事情。我希望您能利用本课程的优势
to really understand fundamentals of calculus, how to compute things,
真正了解微积分的基础知识，如何计算事物，
how to draw beautiful plots, et cetera, using the tools that are available to us today
如何使用今天可用的工具绘制漂亮的地块等
and were not even a few decades ago.
甚至不是几十年前
Okay. Who is this course for? You might wonder is this course really for me?
好的。这门课程适合谁？您可能想知道这门课程真的适合我吗？
Am I old enough for it? Am I the right person? Well, it doesn’t matter who you are;
我学龄足够吗？我是合适的人吗？好吧，您是谁都没有关系。
you will enjoy this course. You might be a beginner trying to learn calculus;
您将喜欢这门课程。您可能是尝试学习微积分的初学者；
you’re welcome to the course. You might be a middle schooler, for example, who is ambitious
欢迎您参加本课程。例如，您可能是一名中学生，有进取心
and wants to learn calculus at a very early stage. That’s fine; you can learn it. This course is
并希望在早期阶段学习微积分。那很好; 你将可以掌握它。这门课是
a good place to begin. Or you might be a doctor or engineer who has learned calculus for sure earlier on,
一个很好的起点。或者您可能是一位肯定已经学过微积分的医生或工程师，
but just wants to refresh their memory and learn this wonderful subject again.
但是只想刷新自己的记忆，然后再次学习这个奇妙的主题。
That’s fine; you’re welcome to. You’ll benefit something from this course.
没关系; 我们欢迎您学习这门课程。您将从本课程中受益。
Now that’s specialized people, but really anyone who wants to understand the Wolfram Language
如果你是专业人士，实际上是任何想了解Wolfram语言
and how it applies to calculus is going to find this course extremely beneficial. To me,
以及如何将其应用到微积分领域的人，您将发现该课程极其有益。对我来说，
this course is designed to be for everyone, not any specialty group, and we’ll try and go slow
本课程是为所有人而设计的，而不是针对任何专业群体的，我们将尽力而为
and explain things very, very carefully at every stage. It’s a good point for me to mention that
在每个阶段都非常非常认真地解释事情。对我来说，这是一个好主意
this course arose in an internship project with John Clark. John Clark was with me last summer,
本课程是在与约翰·克拉克（John Clark）进行的实习项目中提出的。去年夏天，约翰·克拉克（John Clark）和我在一起，
and in fact, he was a student at some point at the California Institute of Technology.
实际上，他曾经是加州理工学院的学生。
John is a remarkable person. He learned calculus when he was in the 7th grade. He is a genius,
John是一个了不起的人。他七年级时学习微积分。他是一个天才，
and he did a great job producing the basic material for the course. But my point is that if John,
他在制作本课程的基础材料方面做得很出色。但是我的意思是，如果John
at his age having just finished college, could write the course, you can surely follow
在他刚刚大学毕业的年龄，可以编写微积分课程，你当然也可以。
what I’m saying over here. Do not give up. Keep persevering. The rewards will be immense.
不要放弃。坚持不懈。回报将是巨大的。
I strongly urge you to follow the course all the way through all 40 lessons,
我强烈敦促您在所有40节课程中始终遵循该课程，
and you will have mastered calculus by the time we are done.
到我们完成时，您将掌握微积分。
Okay. Let’s summarize what we have learned today. As a piece of mathematics,
好的。让我们总结一下我们今天学到的东西。作为一门数学，
calculus shows us what we are capable of if we really put our minds to it.
微积分向我们展示了如果我们真正考虑到我们的能力。
Whether Newton or Leibniz or Fermat or Maria Agnesi, these individuals took time off from
无论是牛顿还是莱布尼兹还是费马还是Maria Agnesi，这些人都从
their daily duties to do what interests them most, which is mathematics and calculus,
他们的日常职责是做他们最感兴趣的事情，即数学和微积分，
and that’s why we have this wonderful subject today. Even today, if you want to do
这就是为什么我们今天有这个很棒的主题。即使在今天，如果你想做
if you want to do any kind of science in the broadest sense, whether it’s physical science
如果您想进行最广义的科学研究，无论是物理科学
or social science, you will find calculus is a very useful apparatus which has in fact
或社会科学，您会发现微积分是非常有用的工具
changed our whole view of the world. Now if you are a student, you will more or less
它改变了我们对世界的整体看法。现在，如果您是学生，您将或多或少
certainly at some stage have to do a little bit of calculus, and you should feel proud
在某个阶段必须做一些微积分，并且您应该为自己掌握它而感到自豪。
to have mastered it yourself—beginning with this course, perhaps. That’s the introduction to calculus
以上就是微积分的介绍。
which I have given you today, and in the next lesson, we will begin formally.
这是我今天讲述给您的，在下一课中，我们将正式开始探讨微积分。
It’s all going to be a little more serious and straightforward in some ways because
在某些方面，这将变得更加严肃和直接，因为
we will talk about functions and then slowly progress into the other areas of calculus.
我们将讨论函数，然后慢慢进入微积分的其他领域。
With that summary, I will conclude today’s lesson. It’s been a pleasure to discuss
总结之后，我将总结今天的课程。讨论很高兴
this introduction with you. I hope you have enjoyed a bit from it. Thank you very much.
与您一起介绍。希望您喜欢它。非常感谢你。